Guide to the Paltsits Collection--Ulster County, New York 1643-1829 MS 477
@ 2011 New-York Historical Society
Paltsits Collection--Ulster County, New York
1643-1829
MS 477
@ 2011 New-York Historical Society
0.75 Linear feet (2 boxes)
A collection of 114 items relating to the history of Ulster County, New York, in particular land transactions, legal papers and church records. All were collected by Dr. V.H. Paltsits.
Provenance
Gift, 1948.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers.
Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.)
Historical Note
Ulster County, in southeastern New York State, is bordered by the Hudson River to the east and the Catskill Mountains to the northwest. Its early inhabitants were Algonquian-speaking Indians, such as the Delaware.
1614 Early adventurers came into Ulster County area to trade with the Indians for corn and pelts.
1615 Fur-trading post established on the future site of Kingston.
1652 Handful of settlers from Holland moved down from near Albany.
1653 Land purchased from the Esopus, a tribe of the Delaware Nation, for farming. Built village called Esopus, later Wiltwyck (Dutch for "wild woods"). After skirmishes with Indians, Peter Stuyvesant, Governor of the Dutch colony, brought soldiers up and built a stockade.
1669 Wiltwyck, now part of the English colony, was renamed Kingston.
1677 French Huguenots, under the leadership of Louis Dubois, founded settlement of New Paltz on 36,000 acres of land purchased from the Indians and patented to them by Governor Edmund Andros.
1683 Ulster, one of the original New York counties, was chartered to "contain the towns of Kingston, Hurley, and Marbletown, Foxhall and New Paltz, and all the villages, neighborhoods, and Christian inhabitations on the west side of the Hudson River, from the Murderers Creek, near the Highlands, to the Sawyers' Creek." Named for the traditional Irish province of Ulster, then under the control of James, Duke of York and Albany (later King James II).
1777 Kingston, the county seat, was the first capital of New York State. The state's first legislature, senate and supreme court convened in Kingston and George Clinton was inaugurated there as New York's first governor. In late 1777, British troops entered and burned Kingston, destroying much of the town.
1805 The community survived and Kingston incorporated as a village.
1828 Delaware and Hudson Canal completed. Kingston was the eastern terminus.
Source of Information: French, J.H. The Historical and Statistical Gazetteer of New York State. Syracuse, N.Y.: R.P. Smith, 1860.
Scope and Content Note
The Paltsits Ulster County Collection is made up of a wide variety of materials related to the history of Ulster County, New York. All items were collected by Dr. Victor Hugo Paltsits (1867-1952), an archivist and librarian who was, at one time, head of the Manuscripts Division of the New York Public Library.
Materials within the collection date from the mid-seventeenth through the early nineteenth century. Examples include deeds and other land papers, surveys, court documents, notes, accounts, meeting and court minutes, petitions, reports, maps, receipts, letters, church pledges, marriage records, election tallies and genealogical notes. A large portion of the collection relates to property transactions. Activities of the Dutch Reformed Church are also prominent. In addition to church financing and construction papers, there are also items that relate to the split within the Church (1754-1771) between the Coetus Party (mostly American-born members who favored independence from Amsterdam) and the Conferentie Party (mostly immigrants from the Netherlands who sought to maintain the status quo).
Many of the documents are written in Dutch. The condition of materials in this collection is mixed. Quite a number of items are fragile, while others are in fair to good condition. There are several oversized items in Box 2.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged following the sequence of an item-level inventory created by Dr. Paltsits. For the most part, the items are in a chronological sequence. Copies of Dr. Paltsits' handwritten notes, included within the folders, provide supplemental information and estimated time frames for many of the undated items.
Related Material at The New-York Historical Society
The New-York Historical Society has a significant amount of material related to the early history of Ulster County. Within the Manuscript Department, for example, is another collection of various property records, court documents, correspondence and financial papers - the Ulster County Collection (Call Phrase: Ulster County). There are also individual manuscript items such as the following:
Land Surveys, 1767-[176?] Call Phrase: BV Gale, Samuel
Patent, 1719/20, March 17, Ulster County (N.Y.) Call Phrase: Y1720
The Library contains a number of related volumes such as the following:
Clearwater, Alphonso T., ed., The History of Ulster County, New York. Kingston, NY: W.J. Van Deusen, 1907. (Call Number: F127.U4 C6)
DeWitt, Deweese W. Ulster County's Reformed Church Legacy: a Record of All Dutch Reformed Churches Whose Origin Came from Ulster County, New York. Kingston, N.Y.: Old Dutch Men's Club, Old Dutch Church, 1977. (Call Number: F127.U4D52)
Fried, Marc B., The Early History of Kingston and Ulster County, N.Y. Marbletown, NY: Ulster County Historical Society [1975]. (Call Number: F129.K5 F82)
Sylvester, Nathaniel Bartlett, History of Ulster County, New York: With Illustrations and Biographical Sketches of its Prominent Men and Pioneers. Philadelphia: Everts & Peck, 1880 (Philadelphia: Press of J.B. Lippincott & Co.). (Call Number: F127.U4 S95)
Ulster County Historical Society, Kingston, N.Y., Collections of the Ulster Historical Society, Volume I. Kingston, Hommel & Lounsbery, printers [etc.] 1860-62. (Call Number: F127.U4 U4)
Van Buren, Augustus H., A History of Ulster County Under the Dominion of the Dutch. Kingston, NY: [s.n.], 1923.
Reformed Protestant Dutch Church (U.S.); Reformed Protestant Dutch Church of Kingston, New York.; Accounts.; Church records.; Correspondence.; Deeds.; Kingston (N.Y.); Legal documents.; Maps.; Real property--New York (State)--Ulster County.; Ulster County (N.Y.)
- Box and Folder List
  - Paltsits Collection - Items #1-10, 1643-1700 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Paltsits Collection - Items #11-20, 1686-1712, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Paltsits Collection - Items #21-30, 1703-1722 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Paltsits Collection - Items #31-40, 1724-1732, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Paltsits Collection - Items #41-50, 1734-1761 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Paltsits Collection - Items #51-60, 1742-1760, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Paltsits Collection - Items #61-70, 1761-1768 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Paltsits Collection - Items #71-80, 1769-1778 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Paltsits Collection - Items #81-90, 1779, 1790, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Paltsits Collection - Items #91-100, 1803-1825, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Paltsits Collection - Items #101-112, 1823-1829, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Paltsits Collection - Item #113, 1730 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Paltsits Collection - Item #114, 1785 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Calendar of Documents
  - #1 Data relating to the Pioneers of Catskill, N.Y. (1 p.), 1643-1649 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - #2 Accounts of a brewer in Esopus [Kingston], N.Y. (2 pp.), 1655 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - #3 The debit of Jacob Barentsen [Barensane] as decreed before the court in Wiltwyck (1 p.), 1667 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - #4 Transcript of Latin diploma awarded as Doctor in Medicine to Laurence Van Gaasbeeck (2 pp.), 1674 May 25 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - #5 Marriage bond between Thomas Garton and Ann Nottingham, Marbletown, N.Y. (2 pp.), 1680/1 Mar. 19 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - #6 Minutes, Court of Sessions, Ulster County (8 pp.), 1702/3 Mar. 2, 4 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - #7 Petition of Jacob Gouertle (?), Esopus, N.Y. to Gov. Thomas Dongan for authority to purchase land from the Indians (1 p.), 1681/2 Jan. 24 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - #8 Deed of Esopus Indians to Hendrickus Beekman (3 pp.), 1682 June 24 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - #9 Brief of James Graham to the Ulster County Court of Oyer and Terminer on behalf of the patent rights of James II against Jacob Browne for trespass on the royal domain called "Shawangang." (1 p.) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - #10A Obligations of indebtedness to the Dutch Church, Kingston, from Hendrick Aertse (1 p.), 1686/7 Feb. 23 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - #10B The same from Wesel ten Broeck (1 p.), 1699/1700 Feb. 20 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - #10C Leaves from the Deacons' Book, Kingston (?) (2 pp.), 1686-1687 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - #11A Sums owed to the Deacons' Fund of the Dutch Church, Kingston (2 pp.), 1686-1699 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - #11B Annulment of Wesel ten Broeck's Pledge with interest (1 p.), 1698/9 Feb. 20 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - #12 Petition from Gartrite Bowne to Gov. Benjamin Fletcher re: her land dispute with John Camp (1 p.), 1693? (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - #13A Petition from Gertrick Browne to Gov. Fletcher re: her land on the Plate Creek (1 p.), 1693 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - #13B Council minute; minute of the meeting of the Justices at Kingston (1 p.), 1693 June 6, June 19 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - #14 Warrant from Gov. Fletcher to the Surveyor General of N.Y., for laying out grants in Ulster County for John Van Camp, Gerard, Jacob, and Cornelius Brewerton; John Everston and William Johnson (1 p.), 1693 Apr. 8 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - #15 Report of the Surveyor-General on the land in dispute between Gertuijcht Bruijn and John Van Camp, et. al. (1 p.), 1693 Aug. 29 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - #16 Deposition of Cornelius Cole re land dispute between Gertriet Brown and John Van Camp, et. al. (1 p.), 1693 Oct. 4 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - #17 Minutes of a Meeting of the Justices at Kingston hearing Indian testimony in Brown vs. Van Camp (1 p.), 1693/4 Mar. 9 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - #18A Minutes of the Provincial Council of New York held at Ft. William Henry to Adjudicate the dispute between Gertruy Bruiyn and John Van Camp et. al. (1 p.), 1694 Sept. 13 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - #18B Map of the land in dispute (1 p.) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - #19 Quit Rent receipt from Thomas (?) Noxon to Soveryen Ten Hout, Kingston (1 p.), 1697 Jan. 20 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - #20 Accounts for use of the poor, New Paltz (?) (7 pp.), 1698-1712 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - #21 List of persons and amounts paid by them for letters patent of the town of Marbletown (fragment), 1703, 1704 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - #22 Letters patent to Col. Henry Beekman, Capt. Thomas Garton and Capt. Charles Brodhead for the freeholders of Marbletown (6 pp.), 1703 June 25 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - #23 Deacons' Poor Fund of Dutch Church of Kingston (4 pp.), 1703/4 Jan., 1706/7 Jan., 1710/1 Feb., 1711 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - #24 Articles of Agreement between David Dubois and Hendrick Janse Cartwright (1 p.), 1704 Mar. 29 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - #25 Acknowledgement of Domine Johannes Petrus Nucella to the Consistory of Kingston that he has been fully paid, 1704 Apr. 11 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - #26 Salary pledges made for the Domine, Ulster County (8 pp.), 1708-1722 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - #27 ALS Domine Gualterus Der Bois to the Consistory of Kingston (4 pp.), [1709-1710] (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - #28 Record of Accounts due to Domine Petrus Vas, Kingston (2 pp.), 1719 Mar. 4, Aug. 11 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - #29 Last will and testament of Richard Brodhead, Marbletown (2 pp.), 1721 Sept. 25 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - #30 ALS Johannes Janson, New York, to Capt. Egbert Schoonmaker (2 pp.), 1722 Mar. 16 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - #31 Release from Quit rent, and partition, from Col Jacob Rutson, Thomas Jansen, Martin Bogard, Angeltie Mowrets, and Rachael Bogard to William Nottingham (1 p.), 1724 May 5 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #32 Minutes, Ulster County Court of Sessions, regarding pay for services by the militia on the frontiers (4 pp.), 1724 July 4, Aug. 20 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #33 Expenses for travel through Connecticut and Rhode Island (3 pp.), 1725 Apr. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #34 ALS William Nottingham to Thomas Sanders (1 p.), 1725/6 Mar. 22 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #35 Letters of Administration under the will and probate of Johannes Westbrook (1 p.), 1727 Apr. 10 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #36 Receipt from Daniel Brodhead to Jacobus Brujn for a lawyer's fee, 1728 June 29 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #37 Will of Jacob Rutsen (fragment) (4 pp.), 1728/9 Feb. 2 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #38 Marriage record of a son and daughter of the owner of Foxhall (fragment), [1730s] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #39 Obligation of Stephen Nottingham, Marbletown, to William Nottingham, et. al. (2 pp.), 1730 Dec. 7 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #40 Letter of the Classis of Amsterdam regarding the complaint against Domine P. Van Driesen for having put his brother over the Claverack, N.Y. church (2 pp.), 1732 Sept. 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #41 Will of Mathys Ten Eyck, Hurley, N.Y. (3 pp.), 1734 Aug. 3 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - #42 ALS Johannis Jansen to Augustus Jay (2 pp.), 1736 Aug. 29 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - #43 ALS Henry Beekman, Dutchess County, to Capt. James Scott, New York (1 p.), 1737 July 11 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - #44 Front leaf from the minute book of the Ulster County Court of General Sessions of the Peace, begun 1738; also includes page of legal forms to be used by the Court in various matters (2 pp.) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - #45 Deposition of Johannis Evertsen, Cooper, before Edward Holland, Mayor of Albany, declaring James Mac Bride had stolen a horse (1 p.), 1739 Sept. 27 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - #46 Receipt from Robert Livingston, Jr. to Jacob Hasbrouck, 1741 July 7 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - #47 Pledge list for the support of the Domine at Rochester (1 p.), 1741 Dec. 15 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - #48 General letter to the Consistories of the 4 Dutch Churches of Rochester, Marbletown, New Paltz and Schawengonek (2 pp.), 1742 Feb. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - #49 Conditions for financing and building a church [in Ulster County] (4 pp.), 1742 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - #50 Five items relating to Petrus Smedes and his controversies with the Consistory of the Dutch Church, Kingston (12 pp.), 1743, 1759, 1761 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - #51 Contributions toward the salary of Domine Mantius from the church at Rochester (3 pp.), 1743 May 20 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - #52 Ulster County Court of Common Pleas: Minutes of Benjamin Davis vs. John Elting, an excise case (1 p.), 1742 Sept. 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - #53 Account of goods and liquors the Justices ordered to be given to the Indians (1 p.), 1745 May (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - #54 Ground plan for a Dutch Church, [c1745] (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - #55 Letter, author unknown, Rosendale, N.Y., to Speaker of the Assembly explaining why he cannot be present (1 p.), 1747 Apr. 8 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - #56 ALS Andreas De Witt, Jr., Warwasing, to Charles De Witt, Livingston Manor (1 p.), 1751 Apr. 8 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - #57 Document explaining that Johannis Krom brought the house of Simon Van Wagenen for the Domine (Marbletown, N.Y.) (1 p.) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - #58 Abstract of letter from the Classis of Amsterdam (1 p.), [late 1760s] (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - #59 Memorandum from the Dutch churches on why they cannot aid German churches in Pennsylvania (1 p.), [late 1760s] (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - #60 Domine Johannes Ritzema to the Classis of Amsterdam regarding the reunion of Coetus and Conferentie factions (7 pp.), 1760 May 7 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - #61 ALS Jacob Ten Broeck to Cornelius Ten Broeck, Rocky Hill, N.J., announcing the death of their mother (1 p.), 1761 Feb. 23 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - #62 Draft of a letter to the Classis of Amsterdam concerning the quarrel in the Dutch churches in America (1 p.), 1763 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - #63 Supervisors of Albany to the N.Y. Legislature in regard to tax relief (2 pp.), 1765 Feb. 2 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - #64 Subscription list for paying Domine Michael Christian Knoll, Lonenborg (?), 1765 Mar. 9 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - #65 Codicil to the will of Nicholas De Myer, Esopus, N.Y., disposing of his slaves (1 p.), 1766 Feb. 10 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - #66 Subscription list for building a church at New Paltz (1 p.), 1766 Aug. 29 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - #67 Subscription list for purchasing a parsonage at Rochester (3 pp.), 1767 Mar. 10 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - #68 Public Notice of the sale of the farm and property of Timothy Davis of the Precinct of the Walkill (1 p.), 1767 Oct. 10 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - #69A ALS Jacob Ten Broeck, Sopis [Kingston] to Cornelius Ten Broeck, Rocky Hill, N.J. (1 p.), 1767 Nov. 21 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - #69B ALS Gerretje Ten Broeck to her sister (?) apparently telling of British raids in the Highlands (fragments), 1777 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - #70 Letter from the Classis of Amsterdam to the Coetus in America (4 pp.), 1768 Oct. 3 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - #71 ALS Domine Romeyn, Marbletown, to Elder Bevier regarding conference with Domine Rysdyk, 1769 June 3 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - #72 ALS Domine John Henry Livingston to Domine Jacob Rutsen Hardenbergh concerning reconciliation of factions in the Dutch church (2 pp., letter incomplete), [before 1771 May] (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - #73 Tally of the election of new officers, Dutch Church, Kingston, 1772 May 12 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - #74 Draft of a letter to George Clinton (1 p.), 1773 Feb. 2 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - #75 Certificate issued to Maria Ten Broeck allowing her to take Communion, Kaetsbaen, 1773 Feb. 9 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - #76 Survey by Johannes Bruyn of Joseph Sackett's tract on the Dwars Kill, showing adjacent lands of Johannes Hardenbergh, Wilhelmus Terwilleger, etc. (1 p.), 1773 Oct. 5 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - #77 Conveyance by William Nottingham to Stephen Nottingham of land in Rochester (mutilated), 1774 Mar. 24 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - #78 Will of Johannis Folk (Valck) of Church Land (2 pp.), 1775 June 23 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - #79 Oaths of Secrecy and Allegiance to King George III taken before the Committee, John Huston, Colonel (4 pp.), [1770s] (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - #80 Receipts from Charles De Witt and Philip Newkerk to Hurley Township for money they received for building a bridge, 1778 Jan. 3 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - #81 Calendar of commitments of prisoners for crimes in Ulster County (2 pp.), 1779 June 22 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #82 Bond from the minister and officers of the Dutch Church, Kingston, to pay the sum stated to Hendricus Sleight (1 p.), 1782 May 4 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #83 ALS Thomas Ryerson, New Paltz, to Capt. Johannis Hardenbergh, Rosendale concerning the "wretched situation" of Gerard Hardenbergh's family (3 pp.), 1783 Oct. 20 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #84 Tally sheet of electors' names and their votes for members of the Senate and Assembly (2 pp.), 1784 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #85 Account book of the costs of rebuilding the Dutch Reformed Church, Kingston, 1785-1786. (5 pp.) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #86 Receipt to Jacob Marinus Groen, Jr., for payment by him of accounts against the Dutch Church, Kingston, 1786 Mar./Apr. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #87 Bill from Stewart and Jones to Cornelius Johnston for supplies used by the Dutch Church, Esopus, 1788 Sept. 30 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #88 ALS Jacob Ten Broeck, Jr., Kingston, to Cornelius Ten Broeck, Rocky Hill, N.J. (1 p.), 1788 Nov. 25 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #89 Receipt to Joshua Dubois from Joseph Chipp for amount due him by the Dutch Church of Kingston, 1790 June 7 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #90 Draft of letter in debt case of De Witt vs. Borden, undated but second half of 18th century (2 pp.) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - #91 Survey of a lot for a church in Shawangunk (1 p.) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - #92 Survey of land of the Clinton, Freer, Seymour and Mott families (1 p.) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - #93 Memorandum about Abraham Bevier's lot from the Paltz River eastward, etc. (4 pp.) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - #94 Survey embracing from "Prauwanhoack" and "Fertyn Kill" to "City Hudson" to "Causeways Kill," etc. (1 p.) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - #95A Part of a deed from John and Anne Brodhead to Stephen Nottingham (1 p.) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - #95B Tracings of Burhans family autographs (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - #96A New York Court of Common Pleas, Kingston, in the matter of Selah Tuthill vs. Albert, Henry and Levi Pawling, 1803 May 6, July (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - #96B ALS John Hasbrouck, Kingston, to Col. John Jansen of Shawangunk, re Tuthill land, 1825 Mar. 10 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - #97 Miscellaneous surveyors' papers relating to the Minisink Patent in the town of New Paltz and land along the Platte-Kill, Marykill and Shawangunk River (ca. 25 pp.) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - #98 Conversion and confession of Robert R. Brett in his own hand (3 pp.), 1806 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - #99 Will of Abraham Bruyn, Shawangunk (2 pp.), 1813 Oct. 25 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - #100 ALS Lemuel Warner Ruggles to Hon. Charles Bruyn re election returns in the contest Thomas Bruyn vs. Louw (1 p.), [1820s?] (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - #101 ALS Charles H. Ruggles to Charles Bruyn, Shawangunk, concerning Lucas Elmendorf's turnpike plans (1 p.), [1820s?] (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - #102 ALS G.W. Ludlam, Goshen, to Charles Bruyn, Shawangunk, about surveying farm lands (1 p.), 1823 Nov. 21 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - #103 Rentals of men's and women's seats in the Dutch Church, Kingston (2 pp.), 1829 June (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - #104 ALS J.H. De Witt, Kingston, to Charles Bruyn, Shawangunk, concerning the prospects of the election in various Ulster County towns (2 pp.), 1825 Oct. 28 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - #105 ALS Dubois Bruyn, Shawangunk, to Charles Bruyn, Albany (1 p.), 1826 Mar. 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - #106 Birth, marriage and death records, Kingston (fragment), [1700s] (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - #107 Memorandum relating to the lands Soverijn Ten Hondt acquired from the Indians in Esopus, [1700s] (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - #108 DS Robert R. Livingston and George Clinton: "Concluding Argument on part of the Plaintiffs in the Case of the Trustees of the Freeholders and Commonalty of the Town of Kingston against George Atkins and Johannis Hardenbergh," (15 pp.), [1700s] (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - #109A Draft of a petition to the Legislature for David Hasbrouck, et. al., for allocation in a road near New Paltz (1 p.) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - #109B Draft of a petition to the Commissioners of Shawangunk asking to lay out a private road (1 p.) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - #110 Memorandum relating to Domines Hermanus Meyer and Romaine and their involvement in disputes of the Dutch Reformed Church (2 pp.) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - #111 Memorandum relating to land in Shawangunk (2 pp.) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - #112 Genealogical notes relating to families that settled in the Kingston area in the 17th century (4 items) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - #113 Letters of Administration under the will of William Nottingham (7 pp.), 1730 Dec. 7 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - #114 Survey map of Kingston and its environs by John Verkerle, Deputy Surveyor, 1785 June 2 (Box 2, Folder 2)